（裡沙）来てくれたんですね
ありがとう
So you came.
Thank you.
（純一）このラブレター　君がくれたの？
You're the one who wrote this love letter?
はい　そうです
Yes.  That's right.
返事　聞かせてもらえますか？
Could you... give me an answer?
I hope it'll be a good one.
いい返事だったら　うれしいな
あの　僕
君のこと　よく知らないんだ
Um... I don't really know you very well.
Have we met somewhere before?
どこかで会ったことあったかな？
And... are you really okay with someone like me?
それに　本当に僕でいいの？
Of course I am!
あなたが　いいんです！
あなたじゃなきゃ　ダメなんです
I wouldn't want anyone else.
あなたが好きだから
Because you're the one I like...
私じゃダメですか！？
Am I no good?
Not at all!
ううん　君みたいな　かわいい子と
つきあえたら　すごくうれしいよ
I'm overjoyed that I can go out with a cute girl like you!
あッ
そんな…　かわいいだなんて
No way... cute?
I'm so happy...
うれしい
If you're fine with me...
こんな僕で　よかったら
Huh?!
え～ッ　どうしたの！？
W-What's wrong?
I'm happy.
うれしい…　うれしくて
I'm so happy...
I'm happy I was able to tell you my feelings.
あなたに私の思いが届いて
うれしい
私　２年Ｂ組　上崎裡沙は
I'm Kamizaki Risa from class 2-B...
今日から
橘純一君の彼女になります！
And I'll be your girlfriend starting today, Tachibana Junichi-kun!
I'll do anything if it'll make you happy.
私　あなたが喜んでくれるなら
何でもしてあげる
えッ！
あッ
Kimi wa kimi no mama de
You just being you
君は君のままで
Boku wa boku no mama de
And me just being me
僕は僕のままで
Subete wakariaetara
If we could understand each other completely
全て分かり合えたら
UTW Presents
Amagami
SS
UTW Presents
Amagami
SS
Nando mo kisetsu wo kasaneta ne ano hi kara
The seasons have come and gone since that day
何度も季節を重ねたね　あの日から
Kyou made doumo arigatou
And even today, I remain so grateful
今日までどうもありがとう
Semai rojiura mezashi
We head towards a narrow back alley
狭い路地裏目指し
Shiroi iki ga odoru
As our white breaths dance in the air
白い息が踊る
Itai kurai nigitta te wo hiite
You hold me by the hand so hard it almost hurts
痛いくらい握った手をひいて
Kimi wa susunde yuku
And pull me with you as you walk on forward
君は進んでいく
Ima sugu kisu shitakatta
I wanted to kiss you right then
今すぐキスしたかった
Kakureta jihanki no ura
Hidden behind the vending machines
隠れた自販機の裏
Hanikande mitsumeatta
We shyly gazed at each other
ハニかんで見つめあった
Yasashii kimochi afureta
And I was overcome with kind feelings for you
優しいキモチ溢れた
Kimi wa kimi no mama de
You just being you
君は君のままで
Boku wa boku no mama de
And me just being me
僕は僕のままで
Subete wakariaeta nara
If we could understand each other completely
全て分かり合えたなら
Futari wa hitotsu da yo
The two of us would become one
２人は１つだよ
Donna chiisa na shiawase mo
No matter how small it may be
どんな小さな幸せも
Mitsukedaseru ki ga suru yo
We'll surely find happiness
見つけ出せる気がするよ
Yasashiku nareta no wa kimi no okage
I learned to be kind because of you
優しくなれたのは　君のおかげ
I can't wait to have your Oden, Hibiki-chan.
What a shame.  Looks like we ran out of time.
Y-Yeah.
Kamizaki Risa Arc
Truth
Could you come here again during lunch tomorrow?
We'll continue from where we left off then.
Yeah.
Tomorrow at lunch, I'm gonna continue from where I left off with Risa-chan!
I'm home.
Welcome back.
Miya, you know...
Hmm?
I uh... g-g-girl... friend...
（はるか）楽しみだな～
響ちゃんのおでん
What's wrong, Nii-nii?
Uh... it's nothing.
《（チャイム）》
I'll go get changed.
《あッ》
《残念　もう時間みたいですね》
Nii-nii's being weird.
Well, he's always weird anyway.
《明日　また昼休みに
ここに来てくれますか？》
Kamizaki Risa-chan, huh?
《今日の続きは　そのとき》
《うん》
I have such a cute girl for a girlfriend.
〈明日の昼は
裡沙ちゃんと今日の続きを！〉
1600 AD, in the battle of Sekigahara...
（詞）１６００年　関ヶ原の戦いの…
〈裡沙ちゃんのこと〉
I should probably introduce Risa-chan to Umehara and Kaoru.
〈梅原や薫にも　ちゃんと
紹介しておいた方がいいよな〉
〈２年前のクリスマスのことで
心配かけちゃったりもしたけど〉
They've been worried about me since that Christmas incident two years ago...
〈もう　僕は大丈夫だ〉
But I'm fine now.
I'm sure this year's Christmas will be a happy one.
〈今年のクリスマスは
きっとハッピーなクリスマスになるさ〉
Because I have a really cute girlfriend now!
〈何たって
かわいい彼女がいるんだから〉
（チャイム）
〈やっと昼休みだ〉
It's finally lunchtime!
〈早く裡沙ちゃんに
会いに行かなきゃ！〉
I can't wait to meet up with Risa-chan!
あれ　もう来てたの？
Huh?  You're already here?
はい　あの…
早く橘君に会いたくて
Yeah.
Um... I couldn't wait to see you, Tachibana-kun...
そう
I see.
僕も裡沙ちゃんに会いたくて
早く来たつもりだったのに
I couldn't wait to see you too,
so I came here as fast as I could...
負けちゃったね
But you beat me to it.
ちゃんと来てくれて　うれしい
I'm so happy that you came.
あ…　あたりまえだよ
O-Of course I'd come!
その…　裡沙ちゃんと会えて
僕も　すごくうれしいよ
And... I'm also really happy I could see you, Risa-chan.
We're lovers, aren't we?
私達　恋人同士なんですよね？
うん
Yeah.
So when did you first start to... um... like me?
ねえ　僕のこと　いつから　その…
好きだったの？
ずっと　前からです
えッ？
Since a long time ago.
Huh?
ふふふ…　私　橘君のこと
よく見てたんですよ
I've always been watching you, Tachibana-kun.
そう…　だったんだ
Really...
あの　私も聞いていいですか？
Um... can I ask you something too?
何？
What?
私の胸　小さくないですか？
ええッ！
Are my boobs kinda small?
You prefer big ones, don't you?
橘君は　大きい方が好きですよね？
ごめんなさい
私　胸あんまりないから
I'm sorry I don't have much of a chest...
そッ　そんなことないよ
T-That's not true at all!
べッ　別に大きいから
いいものってわけじゃないし
I-It's not like bigger is better.
その…　小さいのは　小さいなりの
良さがあると思うし
And I think there are nice things about small ones too...
ふふッ
無理しなくてもいいんですよ
You don't have to pretend.
橘君
大きい方が好きなの知ってるから
I know you like bigger ones.
えッ！
何でそんなこと知ってるの！？
How do you know that?!
前に見たことあるから
I saw you once before...
本屋さんで　そういう本を
見ているところ
You were reading that kind of book at the bookstore.
Big boobs idol
あッ　あれはその…　梅原の趣味で
Uh... that was um...
That's what Umehara likes!
ぼッ　僕は別に
そういう趣味ってわけじゃないよ
T-That doesn't mean I like the same thing!
No... I'm sure guys like them big.
ううん　男の子は
やっぱり　大きいのが好きだよね
今は小さいけど努力してるし
Mine are small now, but I'm working hard.
成長期だから…
I'm still growing too.
だから　もう少し待っててね
So... wait a little longer, okay?
本当に大きいのが好きって
わけじゃ…　って！
Really, it's not like I like big ones that mu-
努力って何してるの！？
Wait, what do you mean by working hard?!
それは秘密です
That's a secret.
でも　いろいろしてます
But... I'm doing all kinds of things...
All kinds of...
いろいろ？
That's right!
そうだ　裡沙ちゃん
Risa-chan, I'd like to introduce you to my friends...
僕の親友に裡沙ちゃんのことを
紹介したいんだけど　いいかな？
Is that okay?
えッ？
僕の彼女として
As my girlfriend.
ごめんなさい
それは　できないんです
I'm sorry.
We can't do that.
何で？
それだけは　ダメなんです
Why?
That's the one thing we can't do.
橘君と　つきあっているって
いうことは他の人には言えない
We can't let anyone know that we're dating.
言っちゃいけないんです
We can't.
That's why I want to make sure nobody sees us when we meet.
だから　あなたと会うのも
なるべく人に見られないように
しなくちゃいけなくて
学校の中では　この使われていない
準備室でしか会えないんです
We can only meet in this unused preparation room in school.
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry.
I won't tell anyone that we're dating, Risa-chan.
僕が裡沙ちゃんと　つきあっている
ことは誰にも言わない
裡沙ちゃんと会うときは
人目のつかないところで会う
When we meet, we'll meet somewhere secluded.
Tachibana-kun...
橘君…
僕は　その約束を守ればいいんだね
I just have to keep that promise, right?
ごめんなさい…　ごめんなさい
Sorry.
I'm so sorry.
ありがとう
Thank you.
いいよ
It's okay.
（美也）うん？
はあ　はあ…
ここ　夜なら
あんまり人もいないし
People rarely come here at night, so I don't think anyone will see us together here.
ニ人でいるところを
誰かに見られたりしないと思うよ
うん　大丈夫
Yeah, this place is okay.
これってデートだよね？
This is a date... right?
うれしい
そ…　そうだね
I'm so happy.
I-I guess so.
It's a date.
デートだね
But are you fine with this place, Tachibana-kun?
あの　でも
橘君はここで　よかったの？
えッ？
その…
Huh?
I don't think it's a place you like very much.
あんまり好きな場所じゃ
なかったと思ったけど
ああ　もしかして
２年前のこと　知ってるの？
So you know about what happened two years ago?
あッ　はい
Ah... yeah.
そう…　ここで僕　２年前のクリスマスに
フラれちゃったんだ
I see.
I was stood up here on Christmas Eve two years ago.
確かに　あんまりいい思い出の場所
じゃなかったかもね
I guess it's true that my memories of this place aren't exactly great.
But you know...
でもね
これからは　裡沙ちゃんと
I'll remember this place as the place
where we had our first date, Risa-chan.
初めてのデートをした
思い出の場所になるよ
2 days until the
Founder's Festival!
（梅原）大将！
あさっては　いよいよ創設祭だな
Boss!
It's the Founder's Festival the day after tomorrow.
ああ
残念ながら
Yep.
Unfortunately, I still don't have a nice girlfriend.
俺にはまだ　ナイスな彼女がいない
もし万一　当日までに
ステキな彼女が現れなかった場合
If by some freak chance I don't
find one before the day arrives...
大将と一緒に
創設祭を回ってやってもいいぜ
I don't mind walking around the place with you, boss.
Sounds good.
ああ　いいよ
But if I were to suddenly find an awesome girlfriend...
でも僕に突然
ステキな彼女が現れたときは…
悪いけど　一人で回ってくれよな
I'm afraid you'll have to walk around on your own.
おおッ　言うじゃねえか　この～
へへへ…
Oh?
Big words, buddy!
（美也）ねえ　おでんの具に
肉まんって　どうかな？
Hey, how about putting meat buns in the Oden?
What?
やっぱりダメかな？
No good?
I really want to go to the Founder's Festival with you tomorrow...
明日の創設祭　裡沙ちゃんと
一緒に回りたいんだけど
せっかくのクリスマスイブ
Indeed, it's Christmas Eve.
私だって　橘君と一緒に
創設祭を回りたいけど　でも…
I want to tour the festival with you too, Tachibana-kun...
But...
明日だけでいいんだ！
Just for tomorrow!
２年前の失恋のことで　梅原には
Ever since my heart was broken two years ago, Umehara's always been looking out for me.
結構
気を使ってもらったりしたから
かわいい彼女もできたし
もう大丈夫だって言いたいんだ！
But I have a cute girlfriend now.
I want to let him know I'm okay!
少し　考えさせてください
Please let me think about it.
I'll let you know before the Founder's Festival tomorrow.
明日の創設祭の前に
返事をしますから
〈明日の創設祭　裡沙ちゃんと
一緒に回れるかな？〉
Will I be able to go to the Founder's Festival with Risa-chan tomorrow?
はあ…
Ugh!
あ～ッ
せっかく橘君の彼女になれたのに
Now that I'm finally Tachibana-kun's girlfriend, what should I do?!
どうしたらいいの！？
Of course I'd want to go to the festival with him!
私だって
創設祭を一緒に歩きたいよ！
私の彼氏だからって
I want all the girls to see he's my boyfriend so they'll know to keep their hands off!
もう誰も橘君に
言い寄ってこないように
他の女の子達に
見せつけてやりたいよ！
〈でも　今さら私が
橘君の彼女だなんて〉
But...
I can't let people know that I'm his girlfriend at this point.
〈知られるわけには　いかないよ〉
I've done horrible things to every girl who got close to him...
〈私は　これまで橘君に近づく
女の子達に〉
〈ひどいことをしてきたから…〉
Purr, meow!
《何で　あんなに森島先輩と
仲良くしてるの！？》
Why is he getting along so well with Morishima-senpai?!
Meow!
《確か　橘君をフッたはずでしょ！》
Didn't she already reject him?!
No, of course not.
《まずいよ　このままじゃ
もしかしたら》
This is bad.
In fact, I loved it!
They might grow close and even start dating at this rate!
《いい感じになって
つきあっちゃうかもしれない》
《〈そんなのダメ〉》
I can't let that happen.
He might be hurt like he was two years ago.
《〈もしかしたら　２年前みたいに〉》
《〈橘君が傷つくことに
なっちゃうかもしれない〉》
I have to protect Tachibana-kun.
《〈私が橘君を守らなくちゃ〉》
《（はるか）私に　ご用があるって
いうのは　あなた？》
So you have some business with me?
《はい　あの…
これを見てほしいんです》
Yes.
Um... I'd like you to see this.
《これって…　橘君の写真？》
《はい》
Is this a picture of Tachibana-kun?
Yes.
《一緒に写ってる子って
もしかして…》
And could this girl with him in the picture be...
《はい　つきあってる人みたいです》
Yes, she seems to be his girlfriend.
So after seeing the two of you get along so well, I felt the need to let you know.
《だから最近先輩が
橘君と仲良くしてるのを見て》
《お伝えしなきゃって思って…》
I'm surprised.
《びっくりだね》
《はい　私も驚きました》
Yes, I was surprised myself.
《こんなすごい写真　見せられたら
もう何も言えないわ→》
Well, I have nothing more to say now that I've seen this photo.
I'll be sure to stay away from him so I don't give him the wrong impression.
《これからは
勘違いされないように→》
《橘君に
近づかないようにしないとね》
《ごめんなさい》
《いいのよ》
I'm sorry.
It's fine.
《教えてくれて　ありがとう》
Thanks for telling me.
《じゃあね》
See you.
《〈先輩　ごめんなさい〉》
Senpai, I'm sorry.
《〈でも仕方ないよね？〉》
But it's for the best.
《〈私が橘君を守らないと…〉》
I have to protect Tachibana-kun.
《〈ちょっと！　何でバイト先でも〉》
Wait a minute, why is she being so friendly with him at work?!
《〈そんなに
仲良さそうにしてるの？〉》
《〈ていうか
ちゃんと仕事しなさいよ！〉》
Actually, do your damn job!
They're supposed to be just friends!
《〈ただの友達だったはずなのに〉》
《〈もう　ほっとけないよ〉》
I have to do something.
《（薫）これって　そういうこと？》
Is this what I think it is?
《はい　そういうことだと思います》
Yes.
I'm pretty sure it is.
《棚町さんが
知らないみたいだったから》
Since you didn't seem to know about it, Tanamachi-san...
《教えてくれて　ありがとう》
Thanks for letting me know.
He's being so distant.
《あいつも　水くさいわよね》
He should've just told me he had somebody already.
《こういう人が　いるんなら
早く言いなさいっての》
And here I was getting all excited...
《勝手に舞い上がっちゃって
私　バッカみたいじゃない》
I feel like an idiot.
《〈ごめんなさい
でも　仕方ないよね？〉》
I'm sorry.
But it's for the best.
《〈ちょっと　ちょっと〉》
Instructor, I see her as a vending machine!
Wait, now he's getting close with that underclassman?!
《〈今度は　あんな下級生と
仲良くなっちゃうなんて！〉》
All right, now try again!
I know Tachibana-kun is a wonderful person...
《〈確かに
橘君はステキな人だけど〉》
《〈でもダメだよ！〉》
But this isn't good!
《〈おとなしそうな子だから
かわいそうだけど〉》
I feel bad for her since she seems like a timid girl, but...
It's for the best.
《〈仕方ないよね？〉》
Excuse me, do you have a moment?
《ごめんなさい
ちょっと　いいかな？》
Y... Yes?
《（紗江）あッ　はい…》
《〈すごいショックだったみたい〉》
She looks really shocked.
I'm sorry.
《〈ごめんね
かわいい子だったから〉》
I'm sure she'll find someone else right away since she's so cute.
《〈きっと　すぐにまた
いい人が見つかるよね？〉》
Her boobs are huge though.
《〈それにしても
あの子の胸　大きかったなあ〉》
《〈橘君　やっぱり胸の大きな子が
好きなのかな？〉》
I wonder if Tachibana-kun really prefers girls with bigger boobs...
Then... I'm sorry, but could you
wait for me until practice is over?
《（逢）それでは　すみませんが
部活が終わるまで》
《待っていてもらえますか？》
《うん　いいよ》
Yeah, sure.
《部活が終わるまで橘君のことを
待たせておくなんて》
Making Tachibana-kun wait until practice is over?
《何なの　あの子！》
What's wrong with her?!
Don't tell me she's already acting like she's his girlfriend?
《もしかして　もう彼女気取り
なんじゃないでしょうね》
《そんなのダメなんだから！》
I can't let that happen!
《というわけだから橘君には　もう
つきあってる子がいるんだ》
So that's how it is.
Tachibana-kun already has a girlfriend.
Sorry.
《ごめんね　こんなこと
私が言うの　おせっかいだよね》
I know it's not really my place to have told you this...
《別に構いませんよ》
Doesn't really matter to me.
Thank you for letting me know.
《教えていただいて
ありがとうございました》
I'll be careful not to give him the wrong impression.
《誤解されないように
これからは気をつけます》
Huh?  It didn't seem like much of a shock to her.
《〈あれ　あんまりショックじゃ
なかったのかな？〉》
《〈でも　その方がいいよね〉》
But I guess that's a good thing.
《〈私も少し気が楽だし〉》
I won't feel quite as bad for doing this...
Ouch!
《逢）痛ッ！》
So it was a shock to her...
《〈やっぱり　ショックだったのかな？
ごめんね〉》
I'm sorry.
《〈ただの幼なじみのはずなのに〉》
She's supposed to just be his childhood friend, but they've suddenly gotten really close!
《〈何だか急接近してるみたい
このままじゃマズイよ〉》
I can't let this continue.
I don't want to hurt her since she's my classmate, but...
《〈クラスメートだし　あんまりかわいそう
なことはしたくないけど…〉》
Junichi...
《桜井さ～ん　元気出してね》
Sakurai-san, cheer up!
Sorry to make you come with me like this.
She's taking advantage of Tachibana-kun's good nature and working him so hard...
《〈人のいい橘君をあんなふうに
こき使うなんて　許せない！〉》
Not at all.  Let me know if you need anything else.
Unforgivable!
《最近　実行委員になったのを
いいことに》
It looks like she's been using him to do all
kinds of work after he joined the committee.
《いろいろ仕事を
手伝わせているみたいだし》
Wait, is she after Tachibana-kun himself?!
《もしかして橘君のことを
狙ってるんじゃないかな？》
《だとしたら　ほっとけないよ！》
If that's the case, I must do something!
Hmph.
《（詞）ふんッ》
Ayatsuji-san, so that's who you're really are...
《〈絢辻さん　あんな子だったんだ〉》
《〈普段のキャラと
全然違うじゃない〉》
She's like a completely different person!
《〈あれじゃあ　橘君
簡単にだまされちゃうよ〉》
She'd have no problems deceiving Tachibana-kun for sure.
I'm glad I was able to protect him.
《〈ちゃんと　私が
守ってあげられてよかった〉》
〈２年前のことさえなければ
私だって〉
If that incident two years ago had never happened...
I could've just confessed to him normally without having to get in everyone's way.
〈みんなのジャマなんかしないで〉
〈普通に告白できたのに〉
Huh?  Tachibana-kun?
（美佳）あれ　橘君？
Makihara... san?
蒔原…　さん
久しぶりだね
It's been so long!
So you're attending Kibitou right now?
（美佳）橘君　輝日東に
入ったんだっけ？→
That uniform looks good on you.
制服　似合ってるよ
蒔原さんは輝日南？
And you're attending Kibina?
うん　ウチから近かったからね
Yep.
It's close to where I live.
〈どうして蒔原さん〉
How is Makihara-san able to speak to me so casually?
〈こんなに普通に
僕と話ができるんだろう？〉
〈僕は２年前　蒔原さんに
クリスマスデートをすっぽかされて〉
She's the one who stood me up for our Christmas date two years ago...
〈フラれたはずなのに〉
あのさ　ずっと橘君に
You know...
There's something I've always
wanted to ask you, Tachibana-kun.
聞きたかったことが
あったんだけど
聞いてもいいかな？
Can I?
Huh?  What is it?
えッ　ああ　何？
That day... Christmas, two years ago...
あの日…　２年前のクリスマスの日
何で待ち合わせの場所に
来なかったの？
Why didn't you show up where we were supposed to meet?
Huh?!  But...
えッ！？　そんな…
僕　ずっと
この公園で待ってたのに
I waited in this park the whole time!
あれ？
だって待ち合わせの場所は
Huh?
Didn't you change the meeting place?
あなたが変えたじゃない
I never did that.
そんなこと　してないよ
But a girl in our class told me you
wanted to change the meeting spot.
でも私　あなたから
待ち合わせ場所を変えたいって
伝言をクラスの子から聞いたから
ずっと映画館の前で待ってたのに
I was waiting in front of the cinema for ages.
そんなの知らない
I don't know how that happened.
ほら　誰だったかな？
Well... you know her?
あんまり目立たない子だったけど
あの子
She doesn't exactly stand out, but that one girl...
Kibitou High School
Founder's Festival
ああ　いらっしゃい
Welcome.
Did you think about going to the festival with me?
一緒に創設祭を回ること
考えてくれた？
ああ　私　橘君さえいてくれれば
創設祭なんて別に…
T-The festival doesn't matter as long as you're by my side, Tachibana-kun...
もしかして
僕と一緒にいるところを
Is it because you don't want to be seen with me?
人に見られるのがイヤなの？
Maybe we don't make a good couple...
僕　裡沙ちゃんと
釣り合ってないかな？
そんなこと！
That's...
That's not it at all!
そんなこと　あるわけない！
But I can't.
でも　無理なんです
I really don't have the right to go out with you.
あなたと　つきあう資格が私には
本当はないから
教えてほしい！　裡沙ちゃんは
何を僕に隠しているの？
Please tell me.
What are you hiding from me, Risa-chan?
I'm sure you'd hate me if you knew everything.
全部　知ったら　きっと私のこと
嫌いになっちゃう
だから　話したくない
That's why I don't want to tell you.
I like you, Risa-chan.
僕は裡沙ちゃんのことが好きだ！
だから　裡沙ちゃんが
一人で苦しんでるのが僕もつらい
So seeing you suffer alone like this is hard on me too.
お願いだから話してよ！
I'm begging you, please tell me.
Okay.
いいよ…
じゃあ　教えてあげる
I'll tell you.
あなたが２年前のクリスマスに
The fact that you were stood up on Christmas two years ago...
待ち合わせをすっぽかされて
フラれたこと
That was my fault.
あれは　私のせいなの
えッ？
It's because she was waiting with all her classmate friends at the meeting place...
だってあの子　待ち合わせの場所で
クラスの友達と待ち伏せて
その場でフッてやろうって
She was going to dump you right there.
みんなで楽しむために
They were going to make a joke out of
your date invitation just to have some fun.
あなたのデートの誘いを
ふざけて受けて…
It doesn't look like you remember...
あなたは　覚えてないみたいだけど
But I was in the same class as you at the time, and they invited me as well.
私は　あのとき
あなたと同じクラスだったから
彼女達から誘われたの
許せなかった
It's unacceptable.
Even though I've always truly loved you, Tachibana-kun,
私は橘君のこと
ずっと本気で好きだったのに
あなたが好きになった人ならって
諦めようとしてたのに
I was going to give up if she really did like you.
だから　私
あなたの伝言だって言って
That's why I lied to Makihara-san
that you had changed the location.
蒔原さんに
嘘の待ち合わせ場所を伝えたの
So Risa-chan was who Makihara-san was talking about.
〈蒔原さんが言ってたのは
裡沙ちゃんのことだったのか…〉
でも結局　あなたはあのとき
But in the end, you were terribly hurt that day.
とても傷ついてしまった
だから　私
So I felt responsible that I wasn't able to protect you that day...
あのとき　あなたを
守れなかった責任を感じて
あなたに告白しないって決めたの
And decided to never confess my feelings to you.
But recently, you seemed ready to move on from what happened two years ago.
でも最近　あなたが２年前のことを
やっと
忘れようとしてくれたみたいで
積極的に女の子と
仲良くするようになって
You actively got friendly with other girls.
And I started to think...
私　思ったの
What if Tachibana-kun gets hurt by another girl again?
また橘君が他の女の子に
傷つけられたら　どうしようって
And so I thought of becoming your
girlfriend and protecting you forever!
だったら　私が橘君とつきあって
ずっと　守ってあげようって考えた
それで…
そう
So you...
Yes.
それで　おもいきって
あなたに告白したんです
I gathered my courage and confessed to you.
So that's why.
そうだったんだ
でも　それなら別に僕と
つきあってることを知られても
But if that's the case, what's the problem with us going out?
問題ないんじゃないの？
蒔原さんは　どうせ
違う学校なんだから
Makihara-san's attending a different school, and I barely see her.
めったに会うこともないだろうし
それだけじゃないの
That's not all.
Lately, whenever it seemed like things
were going well between you and a girl...
最近　あなたが
仲良くなった女の子と
うまくいきそうになったら
I intervened.
私　妨害してたの
I told them you already had a girlfriend and showed them a doctored photo.
あなたには　もう　つきあってる
女の子がいるって言って
でっちあげの証拠写真まで
つくってみせて
Why would you do that?
何で　そんなことを…
言ったでしょう
It's like I said.
I didn't trust any girl other than myself to not hurt you.
他の女の子じゃ　あなたを
傷つけるんじゃないかと思って
And that's why I ended up hurting many other girls.
だから私　そうして　いろんな
女の子のことを傷つけたの
I told myself it was to protect you...
あなたを守るためだって
思い込んで
でも　本当は
ただのヤキモチだったのかもしれない
But in the end, maybe I was just jealous of them.
橘君を取られたくなかっただけ
I just didn't want them to take you from me.
だから　そんなこと
しちゃってたから
Since I did all that, I can't just tell them we're dating.
今さら　橘君と私が
つきあってるなんて言えないの
Why do you care for me so much?
どうして　そんなに僕のことを
好きでいてくれるの？
It doesn't look like you remember...
あなたは
覚えていないみたいだけど
私は
小学校も　あなたと一緒だったの
But I was in the same elementary school as you too.
転校生だったから　途中からだけど
I transferred in, though that was during mid-year...
Sorry, I don't remember.
ごめん　覚えてない
ううん　いいの
私は地味な子だったしね
It's okay.
I was a rather plain girl after all.
So it was when I'd just transferred in,
had no friends, and didn't know what to do.
でね　転校してきて
まだ友達もいなくて心細かった頃
ウチの小学校　給食を残したり
するのに厳しかったでしょ？
They were really strict about leaving food on your tray in that school, remember?
U-Uh... yeah.
うん
私　牛乳がすごく苦手で
I really didn't handle milk very well...
But we weren't allowed to leave anything on our tray.
だけど
残しちゃいけないって言われて
However, there was a boy who'd drink it for me.
でも　そのとき　私の牛乳を
飲んでくれた男の子がいた
それが　あなた
That was you.
After that, you'd always come and drink my milk for me.
私の牛乳を
それからずっと飲んでくれた
それだけ？
That's it?
他の人には　それだけって
思えるかもしれない
That's probably what it looks like to others.
But to me, it was something very special.
でも私にとっては特別なこと
私は　それから
ずっとあなたのことが好きで
I've been in love with you ever since...
あなたを見てきたんです
I've only had eyes for you.
I'm sorry.
ごめんなさい
That's why I can't go with you to the Founder's Festival.
だから　あなたと
創設祭を回ることはできません
私のせいで今年も
楽しいクリスマスにしてあげられなくて
I'm also really sorry you can't have a fun Christmas again this year because of me.
本当に　ごめんなさい
But my dream came true in the short period where I was your girlfriend...
でも　あなたの彼女だった短い時間
私は夢が　かなって　すごく…
幸せでした
I was really happy.
ありがとう
Thank you.
今度は　一緒に
来年の創設祭を回ってくれる
Please find a girlfriend you can have fun with for next year's festival.
彼女をつくってください
もう　私は邪魔しないから
I won't get in the way anymore.
きっと橘君なら　すぐステキな人が
見つかると思います
I'm sure you'll find someone wonderful right away.
So...
じゃあ　さようなら
Goodbye.
Wait.
待ってよ
Risa-chan, are you going to dump me too?
裡沙ちゃんも僕をフルの？
No!
違う　そうじゃない！
That's not it!
Are you going to leave me with
another painful Christmas memory?
また僕に悲しいクリスマスの思い出を
増やすんだ
そんなこと
私だってしたくないよ
Of course I don't want to.
でも…
もう寂しいクリスマスはイヤだ
But...
I'm sick of being lonely at Christmas.
ダメだよ
No...
I want you to always be by my side.
君に　ずっとそばに　いてほしい
私には　そんな資格ないよ
I don't have the right to.
裡沙ちゃんが好きだ
I like you, Risa-chan.
うッ　うう…
今から　一緒に謝りにいこう
Let's go apologize together.
えッ？
一緒に
Let's go together and apologize to the people you lied to.
裡沙ちゃんが
嘘をついた人達に謝りにいこう
そして二人が今　つきあってるって
ちゃんと言おう
And let's tell them that we're dating.
私のこと　許してくれるの？
You'll forgive me?
I finally understand just how much you love me, Risa-chan.
裡沙ちゃんが僕のことを
どれだけ好きでいてくれたのか
やっと分かったよ
いきなり告白されて
でも人には言っちゃダメで
You confessed out of the blue but didn't want anybody to know, so I wasn't really sure what you wanted.
何だか僕　不安だったんだ
だから　やっと本当のことが
分かって　すっきりした
That's why I feel a lot better now that I know the truth.
これから　ちゃんと
つきあっていくために
Let's wrap everything up so we can date with no regrets.
ちゃんとしにいこう
No.
ダメ
えッ？
Not together.
一緒にはダメ
This is something I have to do.
これは私が　ちゃんとしなきゃ
いけないことだから
だから　私が一人でいってくる
So I'll go take care of it by myself.
裡沙ちゃん
Risa-chan...
I'm going to go apologize to everyone.
今から　みんなのところへ
謝りにいってきます
When I return, will you please join me at the Founder's Festival?
戻ってきたら一緒に
創設祭を回ってくれますか？
うん　待ってるよ
Yeah, I'll be waiting.
私　橘君とイカ焼きが食べたい
I want to eat grilled squid with you!
分かった　イカ焼き食べよう
Okay.  Let's do that.
Well, I'll get going.
I'll be waiting.
R-Risa-chan?
Deejishichyun saa!
It's something they say in Okinawa, where I used to live.
I've always wanted to say it to you.
What does it mean?
It's embarrassing, so I'm keeping it a secret.
I'll tell you someday.
Okay, I'll get going for real now.
Deejishichyun saa.
I love you!
TL Note: That's what "deejishichyun saa" means.
Netemo sametemo koishikutte
I miss you in my sleep and when I'm awake
寝ても覚めても恋しくって
Zutto mitsumete ita no
I've always had my eyes on you
ずっと見つめていたの
Ukarehashaideta yuugure mo
On happy and joyful nights
浮かれはしゃいでた夕暮れも
Ochikonda hi mo
And on sad and lonely days
落ち込んだ日も
Yorisou kata ga atatakai
Your shoulder feels warm next to mine
寄りそう肩が　あたたかい
Mune ga kurushii
My heart is aching
胸が苦しい
Gyutto shite
Hold me tight
ギュッとして
Dare yori mo zutto suki datta
I've always loved you more than anyone else
誰よりも　ずっと好きだった
Seiya no hi musubareru
We're joined together on this holy night
聖夜の日結ばれる
Anata no koto ga daisuki yo
I love you so much
あなたの事が　大好きよ
Itsumademo
Forever and ever
いつまでも
Preview
Next episode preview.
Nii-nii, it's finally my turn to be the heroine!
Will you be okay?
Can you really do it?
We'll show everyone how bright our world of love is, Nii-nii!
Don't show that kind of thing!
Risa-chan?!
Where did you come from?
What's wrong with me being in the preview?!
Unlike the ever-present Miya-chan, I barely got any screen time!
Next episode: "Little Sister".
Next Episode
Tachibana Miya Arc
Little Sister
Risa-chan, Miya-chan, make sure you do a good job.
Huh?  I have more screen time?